sqlmanager.net 2011-01-08

# EMS SQL Manager - Privacy Policy

Protecting your privacy is important to EMS. We strive to keep your personal information confidential. By ensuring that you are aware of and understand the EMS Customer Privacy Policy, we can provide you with better service. Please take a moment to read the following policy to learn how we handle your personal information. 

**Collection of Personal Information**  
In order to give you superior customer service, EMS collects your personal information in several ways. For example, EMS may ask you to provide certain information such as your first and last name, mailing address (including zip code), e-mail address, employer, job title and department, telephone and facsimile numbers, and other personal information. When ordering products or services on the Site, you may be asked to provide a credit card number. Depending upon the activity, some of the information that we ask you to provide is identified as mandatory and some as voluntary. If you do not provide the mandatory data with respect to a particular activity, you will not be able to engage in that activity. 

When you use the Site, EMS or third parties authorized by EMS may also collect certain technical and routing information about your computer to facilitate your use of the Site and its services. For example, we may log environmental variables, such as browser type, operating system, CPU speed, and the Internet Protocol ("IP") address of your computer. We use these environmental variables to facilitate and track your use of the Site and its services. EMS also uses such environmental variables to measure traffic patterns on the Site. Without expressly informing you in each particular circumstance, we do not match such information with any of your personal information. 

When you submit personal information to EMS through this Site, you understand and agree that this information may be transferred across national boundaries and may be stored and processed in any of the countries in which EMS and its affiliates and subsidiaries maintain offices, including without limitation, the United States. You also acknowledge that in certain countries or with respect to certain activities, the collection, transferring, storage and processing of your information may be undertaken by trusted vendors of EMS. Such vendors are bound by contract to not use your personal information for their own purposes or provide it to any third parties. One instance where this could occur is in conjunction with framed pages in which the URL for the pages is not visible and the pages are being hosted by a vendor of EMS. 

EMS has established relationships with various service providers whose services are available to you from this Site or from web sites that are linked to this Site. Unless expressly provided to the contrary, personal information that you provide while you are visiting a provider’s web site will be subject to the privacy policy posted on such site and personal information that you provide while on this Site in conjunction with a provider’s service will be subject to this Privacy Policy. In the situation where sites have an EMS “look and feel,” and you reasonably believe you are on an EMS site, the site is collecting information in a solely intermediary capacity and does not use personal information for secondary purposes.

In order to reduce errors in our database, authenticate our users and prevent abuse of our system we may on occasion supplement the personal information you submit to us with information from third party sources. For example, we may supplement your registration information with address information provided by the U.S. Postal Service to qualify your information and prevent errors in our database.

**How Your Personal Information is Used**  
EMS uses your personal information for several purposes including: 

  * To ensure our Site is relevant to your needs. 
  * To deliver services, such as newsletters, events, training or software, which you request or purchase. 
  * To help us create and publish content most relevant to you. 
  * To alert you to product upgrades, special offers, updated information and other new services from EMS. 
  * To allow you access to limited-entry areas of our Site as appropriate. 

**When We Disclose Personal Information**  
Because EMS is a global company, your personal information may be shared with other EMS business affiliates around the world. They will protect your personal information in accordance with the EMS Customer Privacy Policy. If you do not want to receive promotional information from EMS or other companies and wish to opt-out, you can disable this subscribe option in your Member account.

EMS works with other companies that help us provide EMS products and services to you, and we may provide your personal information to these companies. For example, we give shipping companies this information so they can deliver your products efficiently. The information they receive is for shipping and delivery purposes only, and we require that the companies safeguard your personal information in accordance with EMS's policies. 

EMS may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or legal process. We may also disclose information about you if we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect the personal safety of EMS employees, users of EMS products or services, or members of the public. 

**How We Protect your Personal Information**  
EMS is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. For example, the EMS Shop uses industry-standard Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption on all web pages where personal information is required. To make purchases from the EMS Shop, you must use an SSL-enabled browser such as Netscape Navigator 7.x, Safari 1.0 or Internet Explorer 5 – 6.x. This protects the confidentiality of your personal and credit card information while it is transmitted over the Internet.

We urge you to take every precaution to protect your personal data when you are on the Internet. Change your passwords often, use a combination of letters and numbers, and make sure you use a secure browser. 

**Access to Your Personal Information/Opt-Out Choices**  
You have access to the information we have about you. To review and update your personal information logon to your Member account and choose [Change My Profile](https://secure.sqlmanager.net/member/profile).

**Collecting Other Personal Information**  
When you browse EMS’s website, you are able to do so anonymously. Generally, we don’t collect personal information when you browse – not even your email address. Your browser, however, does automatically tell us the type of computer and operating system you are using. 

Like many websites, the EMS website uses “cookie” technology. When you first connect to our site, the cookie identifies your browser with a unique, random number. The cookies we use do not reveal any personal information about you. Cookies help us understand which parts of our websites are the most popular, where our visitors are going, and how long they spend there. We use cookies to study traffic patterns on our site so we can make the site even better. 

In some of our email to you, we use a “click-through URL.” When you click one of these URLs, you may pass through our web server before arriving at the website that is your destination. We may track click-through to help us determine your interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. 

**Clear Gifs, Log Files, and Action Tags**  
EMS employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. The main difference between the two is that clear gifs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear gifs are not tied to users’ personally identifiable information.

EMS also uses IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

From time to time, we may use third parties to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet. These third parties may also collect anonymous information about your visits to our web Site. This is primarily accomplished through the use of a technology device, commonly referred to as a Web beacon or an Action Tag, which we place on various web pages within our web Site that allows third parties to collect anonymous information, which cannot be used to identify you personally. These third parties may use information about your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide ads about goods and services of interest to you.

The third parties report the anonymous data that they collect on our behalf back to us, which we link to our customer's personally identifiable information for the purposes of better serving you. When we merge this data, it is treated under this policy as personally identifiable information as described above.

**Our Companywide Commitment to Privacy**  
To make sure your personal information remains confidential, we communicate these privacy guidelines to every EMS employee. In addition, EMS participates in industry initiatives to preserve privacy rights on the Internet and in all aspects of electronic commerce. 

EMS does not knowingly solicit personal information from children or send them requests for personal information.

EMS's website contains links to other sites. EMS does not share your personal information with those websites and is not responsible for their privacy practices. We encourage you to learn about the privacy policies of those companies. 

If we are going to use your personal information differently from that stated at the time of collection, we will try to contact you via email using the most recent information we have. If you have not given us permission to communicate with you, you will not be contacted, nor will we use your personal information in a new manner. 

The EMS Customer Privacy Policy is subject to change at any time. We encourage you to review the privacy policy regularly for any changes. 

**Contact Information**  
EMS welcomes your comments regarding this privacy policy, please contact us at [privacy@SQLManager.net](mailto:privacy@sqlmanager.net)

Last updated November 2005  
© 1999-2005 EMS Database Management Solutions, Inc. All rights reserved.
